

linkedin.com/in/ben-liu github.com/ben196888 (+61) 413 188 912 ben196888@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Ben Liu is focusing on full-stack web apps developing these 5 years. He worked in JavaScript with ReactJS for 3.5 years and NodeJS for 2 years. He is always passionate about new technology and likes to learn new ideas from developer events and open source projects. He is not only an avid problem solver but also a good autodidact who is keen on more than one solution.

SKILLS

Skills JavaScript, TypeScript, Golang, Docker, Python

Libraries ReactJS, Redux, RxJS, NodeJS, Serverless, Restify, Angular, EmberJS

Databases Firebase, Mongo, Redis, PostgreSQL

Tools Jenkins, Buildkite, Kafka, RabbitMQ, Elasticsearch

WORK EXPERIENCE

Predictive Hire, Melbourne, Australia

Oct. 2018-Jun. 2019

Software Engineer

- Designed and built a chatbot for 6000 applicants that brought us a half-million AUD investment.
- \bullet Reduced 600% CI/CD run time by decoupling micro-services in same integration test rate.
- Led 4 Devs and 1 DevOps to start migrating monolithic API services to micro-services.
- Reduced 200% delivery time by decoupling the data models generation and API handlers development.
- Guided 2 data specialists to process and ship 1.5 GB data to customers every month.

Tabcorp, Melbourne, Australia

Developer

Jan. 2017-Sep. 2018

- Led 3 Devs and 1 DevOps to build an API service for 5000 transactions per min in 4 weeks.
- Solved 3rd party API issues across the Ops team and Devs team on production in one day.
- Reduced DOM unit tests 3500% execution time by replacing headless chrome with JSDOM.
- Increased unit tests coverage rate from 75% to higher than 95% by adding 100+ test cases.
- Resolved the browser crashed issue by throttling when receiving 150+/s data stream.
- Unblocked bottleneck to render 500% more transactions per second by queueing the stream.

HopebayTech, Taipei, Taiwan

Feb. 2014-Oct. 2016

Software Engineer

- \bullet Developed an internal people management web service to reduce 100K/yr TWD license fee.
- Created 5 CI pipelines to test, build, and deliver the docker images automatically.
- Dockerized 5 web services, 3 databases, and 2 cross-compiling build systems.
- Integrated Elasticsearch with customed system monitoring APIs for 200-unit servers.

EDUCATION

Bachelor's degree, Mathematics